hi everybody welcome back to the
channnel and today we're going to make
the first pole chosen ice cream which is
butterscotch
honeycomb so to make this ice cream
we're going to need to do a few things
we're going to need to make butterscotch
obviously we're going to make honeycomb
or Cinder toffee or hokey pokei whatever
you call it wherever you live and we're
going to need to make our ice cream
we're also going to do something special
at the end when we dish it up so what
are we going to need for all of these
components for the butterscotch we're
going to need 150 g of brown sugar 90 G
of butter and 90 G of
cream so let's start with that one
before we move on to the next step
butterscotch doesn't have to be
difficult to make so we're going to put
all of our stuff into the pan and heat
it all up we're going to start with our
sugar and then add in our
cream finishing off with our
butter and turn
on the hob and we're just going to leave
it there and boil it for about three to
four minutes so we'll come back once
that's
done here we go so we got the
butterscotch just starting to boil now
just going to turn the heat down a
little bit and keep it there for 3 to 4
minutes so as we're not making
butterscotch candies we don't need to
worry about the temperature of the sugar
all we're trying to do is bring the
flavors together because we're going to
put it in the rest of our ice cream base
ingredients so after a few minutes of
that we're going to take it off the heat
and get started on the next
stage so now that our batters Scotch is
sitting there just chilling out for a
few minutes we're going to get our
ingredients for our ice cream base in
the pan on the hob and and we're going
to incorporate that butterscotch into
this base so what do we need for the ice
cream we're going to need 350 G of milk
350 G of cream at 33% fat 80 g of brown
sugar 10 G of dextrose 90 G of our
butterscotch sauce 55 G of skin milk
powder and 1.5 G of your stabilizer if
you're going to use it if you're not
going to use a stabilizer then I
recommend adding two egg yolks to the
base just to give the
emulsification
required with our Butters Scot just
staying warm on the top there and our
milk and cream here just gently warming
up what we've got here is our brown
sugar our dextrose and our stabilizer so
we're going to just give that a nice
little mix together make sure that
stabilizer is
completely combined with the sugars
we do that just to make sure that the
stabilizer doesn't Clump as soon as it
goes into our
liquid and there we go we're going to
put that straight into our Dairy and
this is just our milk powder nothing
special added in there and we're going
to put that straight in there as well
and what we're going to do is gently
bring that up to
temperature
what we're going to do is gently combine
those ingredients first just for a
couple of minutes and what we're looking
to do is to dissolve that milk powder
into our milk and cream and get those
lumps of brown sugar dissolved in there
as
well that will take just a couple of
minutes of
stirring
and whilst that's warming up we're going
to turn that off and weigh out 90 G of
our butterscotch so lovely and
thick here we go 90
G and then we're just going to add that
in make sure you get all of that in
there let's just get a spoon we don't
want to waste any of this
lovely and keep stirring
that until it comes up to your 80 to 85
CRA to make sure that your stabilizer is
properly hydrated then you're going to
take it off the heat and store it in the
fridge and for the honeycomb candy
you're going to need 200 g of standard
white sugar 100 G of golden syrup and 10
G of baking soda and that's the same as
bicarbonate of soda if you're in
Europe and right here is when I am just
about to put baking powder into my
honeycomb as you can see it's completely
flat very few air bubbles in there hey
this kind of thing happens occasionally
but we're going to pour it into pan and
just see what it looks like anyway but
let's start again what we're going to do
is add our sugar into the pan and to
that we're going to add
in our golden syrup this is just Rogers
golden syrup straight from Walmart
nothing
special like
so and we're going to warm all of this
up to somewhere
around 140 to 100
50° Centigrade okay now we're ready
we're going to turn the heat off and add
in the right ingredient and we're going
to stir
it now that the honeycomb has completely
cooled down you can see we've got two
very different things I didn't realize I
put the wrong thing in here until it was
too late but I thought we'd compare them
while we're stood here um obviously
there a very
distinct difference baking powder is a
very different thing to baking soda and
this is the kind of result it's
completely
flat very little air in there and
obviously this is the this is the
correct one um just before we go any
further what does this one taste
like
tastes okay actually it still tastes
like it should doesn't have anywhere
near as much air in it but the air it
does have is very consistent you know
what that reminds me of that reminds me
of a UK crunchy bar it's the same type
of
bubbles same taste makes me
wonder
not going to waste that
but that's not what we came here for we
came here
for the more
traditional I'm going to call it
honeycomb cuz that's what we call it
back in England but I guess let's call
it honeycomb
toffee what we need to do is we need to
cut this up store what we're not going
to use here in an airtight container
we're going to powder some
and put the rest away so let's get
[Music]
cutting the ice cream is completely
chilled in the fridge we' got a machine
here ready to go we've got our remaining
butterscotch sauce here just going to
show you this has been out not been in
the fridge this has been out overnight
as you can see it's just got a bit of
drag to it get the light reflecting on
it so you can see it's just
horriable um and we've got our powder
we're going to use the powder later so
put that aside let's get the ice cream
base out we'll give it one final stir
make sure it's all completely loose and
we'll get the machine chilled down and
get it
[Music]
churned
we in the last few minutes of churning
just going to take our butterscotch
sauce and pop it in the microwave just
for a few seconds to loosen up just a
touch more we don't really want to heat
this up too
[Music]
much there we go that was just 10c blast
in the microwave obviously you're
looking at Sugar here doesn't take long
to heat up so we've just loosened it
up it's probably something like 25 30
deg something like that there we go you
can just see the pouring consistency
hold
on
almost
there what we're going to do once this
is ready we're going to load in our tub
and then we're going to layer in our
beautiful butterscotch sauce in between
get it in the freezer to completely
harden
[Music]
off
our ice cream is completely Frozen I had
to turn the freezer down a bit and this
is a high pack ice cream so a lot of
sugar in it it will take a while to
freeze think it's what we at 4 hours I
guess that's about right we got
everything we need here to make a really
pretty bowl of ice cream we've got our
refined coconut
oil I don't want anything to taste to
Coconut unless I they choose to so what
we're going to do is we're going to take
some
70% chocolate going to take a
few
butterscotch chocolate chips straight
from
bolb we've got our butterscotch
sauce we've got our powdered honeycomb
we' got the finished honeycomb let's
just get started so in a microwave
Bowl you don't have to be exact
for this we just want
to put enough in there it's probably
something like 50 g
worth let's add a few of the
butterscotch this is
just to add a bit of the butterscotch
flavor so there's
probably about 20 20 25 G of the
butterscotch chips in
there we're going to take I don't want
to use that
spoon whatever don't make any difference
is it we're going to take some of our
refined coconut oil so that's about 10
G I'm going to pop all of that in the
microwave to
melt and there we go that took about a
minute in various lengths so did 10 15
second stints and there we go we're
melted does
it it's got a a tinge of butterscotch to
it that's
nice
right it's a very English word to say
isn't it butterscotch anyway let's get
the ice cream
out let's prepare we got our
powdered get rid of
that got a butterscotch sauce probably
can't see that on camera but let's just
get that there going to yeah we're going
to take a piece of that from
there we going to move these out the way
like
that and
[Applause]
let's dish
[Music]
up
and there we go butterscotch honeycomb
ice cream with a butterscotch chocolate
crackle top and chocolate decorated
[Music]
Honeycut there we go I was just saying
to stat that it was about time we did
Royal we I did you know something that
looked quite pretty so here it is I'll
put the you've seen the beat roll I'll
just put it up but this is the second
attempt of this ice cream the first
attempt didn't make it to camera it
failed miserably for a really weird
reason
um I'll probably do a little short on
that another time
but this one has turned out perfectly
the honeycomb turned out perfectly
Second Time Around interestingly enough
though the failed honeycomb as I said
earlier in the video is incredibly
good
it's just like
crunchy just like a crunchy bar so I
might make crunchy bars in a video
anyway enough
talk let's destroy this work of art and
see what it tastes
[Music]
like it's
buttery it's got like a caramel
smoothness to it it's um my wife is
making you know lovely kind of
Expressions behind the camera but it's
that that butterscotch taste is
different to caramel you know the dark
the difference between butterscotch and
caramel is pretty much just the sugar
butterscotch uses brown sugar caramel
doesn't you can treat them in exactly
the same way
but the honeycomb Flex over the
top you get that touch
of almost burnt sugar from the honeycomb
coming around that drizzle over the top
of the chocolate the chocolate cracks
beautifully well you can
use coconut oil olive oil any oil
essentially but obviously if you use an
oil that's got a flavor then you're
going to impart that flavor into the
chocolate the butterscotch swirl
now in the process of adding the
butterscotch SWR to the ice cream I
affected the the crystal structure of
the butterscotch sauce uh as you noted
it did run now it's kind of gone hardish
you know it's
gone crystally which is kind of what you
don't want to happen when you're making
caramel because you don't want that
lumpy hard sugar to reform and that's
essentially what you're doing when Su
butter scotch or
caramel gets affected by a non-melted
piece of sugar that hard lump of sugar
will then affect the crystal structure
of the rest of your caramel and make it
all go back to that orig that original
state so it'll all go Cris fine in this
kind of situation doesn't matter it's
the
leftovers I'm just going to eat it
straight out the tub
but a lot of
work damn good ice
cream the melting chocolate is a dole to
make you know you're doing three things
you're making a honeycomb you're making
the ice cream you're making a
butterscotch play with what you got this
is the result really bloody good ice
cream I want to thank my Kofi supporters
and YouTube supporters
um you couldn't do this without it cost
a lot of money to make these ice creams
so thank you ever so much for your
support it is really really appreciated
if you're not a subscriber of the
channel then why the hell not and how
did you get this far in this video
without subscribing so come on play the
game subscribe like share do all that
thanks very much for watching I'll
see you next
week
[Music]